<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<search>
  
  
  
  <entry>
    <title>The lore of Azernavia</title>
    <link href="/2022/09/09/test/"/>
    <url>/2022/09/09/test/</url>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>In a time before life, there was void. A world where there was everything and nothing at the same time. Matter and energy existed and perished in a cosmic dance, a symbiotic relationship, a perpetual motion machine that would birth itself time and again. And in that inky paradoxical void where everything lives, and yet nothing survives – something stirred. Life and existence, yearning to break out of the cycle, resisted its collapse. Not much is known of this event, and is currently considered a bustling area of open research at various universities across this world that came to be. All that is known of that time is that somehow, this energy condensed into pockets of matter and stopped its perpetual reincarnation – and thus were born the gods.</p><p>The gods, seeking to reason their existence, their grand purpose, created a young world; A material world contained inside a weave of their magic, where matter and energy could stably exist. It was populated by shards of their energies condensing itself into matter, thereby creating creatures and biomes to populate this young world. A world where there was love and kindness and kinship; but there were balancing counterparts to every quality, it was a world that accommodated malice, prejudice and hatred. The gods sought to give their children the same paradoxical life they seemed to have accidentally acquired – A quest for meaning, a reason to reason their own existence. Azernavia is an old world now, eons upon eons have passed since its creation and the subsequent departure of the gods to other planes keep their creation away from their qualms.</p><p>The name <em>Azernavia</em> has its etymology rooted in a language long lost. The linguists of this age have resigned themselves to calling it the ancient tongue - the first structured language spoken by life that had woken up. It is derived from the words “Azer”, meaning ‘to live’ or in some contexts, ‘the gift of life’ and “Navia”, meaning ‘the (cosmic) ocean’. It is commonly accepted that the word roughly translates to ‘A place that harbors the gift of life in the (cosmic) ocean’. Many archeological, anthropological and linguistic explorations of this language and its associated culture is still pursued at various universities across the world.</p><p>The ancient ones (also referred to as - the elders, The folk of the forest, The wise ones, the first ones), explored this young world, established structured communities, created society, built civilizations, discovered science, mathematics and alchemy, mastered various forms of arcana and advanced the mind far beyond the grasp of the contemporary world. It was a golden age, and like all golden ages, that too came to a close. Wronged by one of their own, deceived by their own hubris, they fell in a cataclysmic collapse that wiped out an entire continent.</p><p>The survivors, after destroying thousands and thousands of manuscripts that spoke of their knowledge and accomplishments; took their pilgrimage away from the material plane, to a place historians have come to call the ‘third scale’ – leaving behind only a few species that would grow and repopulate the abandoned lands. There are numerous contrasting theories concerning the existence, nature and the location of this third scale among the planes – and a consensus has yet to be reached. What the experts do know is that before leaving, they created six elemental relics: conduits that connect the material plane to various other planes. These conduits also seem to regulate the weave of magic and withstand the passage of time. It is understood that these conduits are fail-safe measures that guide the living from extinguishing itself or the weave that it derives all of its powers from. Thus all that is left of their legacy are ruins, forgotten temples and places of ritual hidden deep within jungles and tundra, and the six conduits – humming ad infinitum – keeping the world from a certain collapse.</p><p>Azernavia today, is a bustling world of four continents: Quekora, Reonura, Craefall, Eyush; vibrant with cultures, rich with history, filled to the brim with folks far removed from the grand histories of this tumultuous world. Every now and then ambitious minds arise to disrupt this delicate balance, and it is during those times the world calls out to the most unexpected people to take on an adventure, and ascend the steps of glory…</p>]]></content>
    
    
    
  </entry>
  
  
  
  
</search>
